<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosopher&#39;s Stone on Podtrificus Totalus</title>
    <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/tags/philosophers-stone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosopher&#39;s Stone on Podtrificus Totalus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 07:00:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://podtrificustotalus.com/tags/philosophers-stone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1.17 The Man with Two Faces</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/117/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 07:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/117/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/117TheManwithTwoFaces.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re a little late on this one, but we&amp;rsquo;re finishing off* Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone* on Podtrificus Totalus this week, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On this episode, we talk about the Power of Love, which Harry uses to save the school (and the wizarding world) from Lord Voldemort. Dumbledore lets slip a few truths, the House Cup is doled out, and our trio returns home for the summer break.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.16 Through the Trapdoor</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/116/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 07:00:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/116ThroughtheTrapdoor.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and that means it&amp;rsquo;s time for a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Harry, Ron, and Hermione take their final exams, but Harry is bothered by his scar burning and warning him of approaching danger. They learn that Dumbledore has been summoned away from Hogwarts and realize it is up to them to protect the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone from Snape and Voldemort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.15 The Forbidden Forest</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/115/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 07:00:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/115TheForbiddenForest.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to serve detention and explore the menacing Forbidden Forest on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter read along podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After foolishly forgetting the Invisibility Cloak, Harry and Hermione are caught in their dragon disappearing act by Filch. McGonagall deducts a kiloton of points from Gryffindor House for their transgressions, and Harry, Hermione, Neville, and Draco serve out their punishments in the Forbidden Forest, where a mysterious evil lurks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.14 Norbert the Norwegian Ridgeback</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/114/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 07:00:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/114NorberttheNorwegianRidgeback.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloaks and schemes and dragons, oh my! It&amp;rsquo;s time for another episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quirrell seems to be resisting Snape&amp;rsquo;s efforts to steal the stone, at least long enough for Harry, Ron, and Hermione to be distracted by a sub-plot: Hagrid has obtained an illegal dragon egg, and Malfoy finds out about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.13 Nicolas Flamel</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/113NicolasFlamel.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mysteries are solved and soundboards are abused this week on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, when Harry, Ron, and Hermione at last discover who Nicolas Flamel is and Cassie relives childhood fears.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After giving a bullied Neville a Chocolate Frog card, Harry remembers where he first heard Nicolas Flamel&amp;rsquo;s name. Hermione pulls out a giant book and the trio finally uncovers what Fluffy is guarding. Snape referees Gryffindor&amp;rsquo;s Quidditch match, and Harry overhears a foreboding conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.12 The Mirror of Erised</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/112/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/112/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/112TheMirrorofErised.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, Cassie and Joe get sad during chapter twelve of Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone, &amp;ldquo;The Mirror of Erised.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the Christmas holidays upon Hogwarts, Harry and the Weasleys are left mostly alone to enjoy snowball fights and lavish Christmas dinners, but a mysterious gift enables Harry to explore the castle unseen at night. He discovers the Mirror of Erised, a magical device that shows the viewer their deepest desire. Harry is entranced by the mirror, but at what cost?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.11 Quidditch</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/111/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 07:00:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/111Quidditch.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, Cassie and Joe get physical for chapter eleven of Harry Potter and the Philsopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone, &amp;ldquo;Quidditch.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A November chill has hit Hogwarts in this chapter, requiring Hagrid to, for some reason, defrost the school broomsticks while Harry frets over his first Quidditch match as the Gryffindor Seeker. Harry learns the cause of Snape&amp;rsquo;s apparent limp, then a curse mysteriously befalls his broomstick during the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.10 Halloween</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/110/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/110/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/110Halloween.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, Joe and Cassie get spooky for chapter ten of Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone, &amp;ldquo;Halloween.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Harry and company continue their magical educations in this chapter when they learn the levitation charm Wingardium Leviosa (which also serves as our Spell of the Week). Harry and Ron&amp;rsquo;s rocky relationship with Hermione comes to a head on Halloween, and Hermione is left crying in the bathroom and in mortal danger when a troll gets loose in the dungeon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.09 The Midnight Duel</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/109/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/109TheMidnightDuel.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s right — Podtrificus Totalus is back! After a long interlude, Cassie and Joe pick up once again to do a Harry Potter podcast, chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s episode covers chapter nine of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Midnight Duel.&amp;rdquo; Harry&amp;rsquo;s conflict with Draco Malfoy reaches new heights during flying lessons when Draco snatches Neville&amp;rsquo;s Remembrall. Draco challenges Harry to a duel at night, and Harry, Ron, Hermione, and Neville are left to discover the mystery of the forbidden third floor corridor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.08 The Potions Master</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/108/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:46:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/108/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/108ThePotionsMaster.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time for a slightly late (but no worse for the wear) episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s episode covers chapter eight of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Potions Master.&amp;rdquo; Harry and Ron begin their classes at Hogwarts, where Harry butts heads with Professor Snape, who seems to have a mysterious grudge against him. The mystery of the little package from chapter five also develops in this chapter, with the revelation of a break in at Gringotts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.07 The Sorting Hat</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/107TheSortingHat.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re back after a short break for a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s episode covers chapter seven of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Sorting Hat.&amp;rdquo; Harry and his fellow first-years at last arrive at Hogwarts and face the titular Sorting Hat, who places them into the four houses: Gryffindor, Hufflepuff, Ravenclaw, and Slytherin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and pop culture in this episode, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.06 The Journey from Platform Nine and Three-Quarters</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 09:44:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/106/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/106TheJourneyFromPlatformNineandThreeQuarters.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday and that means we have a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s episode covers chapter six of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Journey from Platform Nine and Three-Quarters.&amp;rdquo; Harry travels to King&amp;rsquo;s Cross station where he meets the Weasleys and befriends their youngest son, Ron, aboard the Hogwarts Express. On the train ride, we&amp;rsquo;re introduced to a heap of new characters, including Hermione Granger and Draco Malfoy, among others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.05 Diagon Alley</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/105/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 10:43:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/105/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/105DiagonAlley.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Podtrificus Totalus is here with a brand new, fashionably late episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week we cover chapter five of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Diagon Alley.&amp;rdquo; In this chapter we at last enter the magical Wizarding World as we follow Harry and Hagrid into Gringotts, the wizard bank, and shops for textbooks, golden cauldrons, robes, an owl, and a wand. Rowling continues to build on the close relationship between Harry and Hagrid in an ultimately eventful and heartwarming chapter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.04 The Keeper of the Keys</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/104/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 02:18:03 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/104/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/104TheKeeperoftheKeys.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re Apparating in with the fourth episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week we tackle chapter four of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Keeper of the Keys.&amp;rdquo; Hagrid arrives to rescue Harry from the evil Dursleys and tells him the truth about his past, his parents, and Lord Voldemort in one of the most forward-moving yet mysterious chapters thus far. As we move through the chapters, we grow ever closer to Harry&amp;rsquo;s arrival at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, and deeper in J.K. Rowling&amp;rsquo;s magical world. We also introduce a new segment on this episode, Spell of the Week, and answer more listener emails.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.03 The Letters From No One</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/103/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 19:28:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/103/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/103TheLettersFromNoOne.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time for a brand new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week we tackle chapter three of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Letters From No One.&amp;rdquo; Harry receives a mysterious letter in the mail which his aunt and uncle seem determined to prevent him from reading. Not too much else happens in this chapter, besides Uncle Vernon losing his marbles, which always proves entertaining, and Dudley&amp;rsquo;s consistently horrifying behavior. With a cliffhanger ending of a loud knock on the door, we grow closer and closer to the magical world of Hogwarts! We also answer our first listener email from our friend PK from India and discuss the possibility of featuring guests in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.02 The Vanishing Glass</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 11:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/102/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/102TheVanishingGlass.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re back with another episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; read along podcast!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With introductions out of the way, we break right into the second chapter of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Vanishing Glass.&amp;rdquo; The chapter turns out to be a real bummer, but at least Harry got a lemon ice pop along the way. The only outside source we reference this time around is (very briefly) Charles Dickens&amp;rsquo; Great Expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.01 The Boy Who Lived</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/stone/101TheBoyWhoLived.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the first episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; read along podcast!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We begin the episode by introducing our hosts, Cassie and Joe, and discussing our intentions for the podcast — to read the &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; series book by book, chapter by chapter, and share our love for the series with each other and our audience. We hope that our listeners will (at best) read along with us or at least share in the experience of this awesome series, regardless of whether you’re a new or old reader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
