<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chamber of Secrets on Podtrificus Totalus</title>
    <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/tags/chamber-of-secrets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chamber of Secrets on Podtrificus Totalus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 07:30:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://podtrificustotalus.com/tags/chamber-of-secrets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2.18 Dobby&#39;s Reward</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/218/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 07:30:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/218/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/218DobbysReward.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, which is the perfect day for Podtrificus Totalus to finish off &lt;em&gt;Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;! This episode is a family affair, too; we are joined by Cassie&amp;rsquo;s sister Becca as a guest and we answer an email from their other sibling, Den.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, Harry, Ron, Ginny, Gilderoy, and Fawkes leave the Chamber and head to Dumbledore&amp;rsquo;s office. There, Harry reveals all the weird goings-ons at Hogwarts this year and how he was able to defeat Tom Riddle. Dumbledore and Harry discuss how our choices define us and why Harry is a true Gryffindor. Harry frees Dobby from Lucius Malfoy with his slimy sock and all the Petrified students are given the Mandrake draught.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.17 The Heir of Slytherin</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/217/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 07:30:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/217/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/217TheHeirOfSlytherin.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s Monday and Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, is here to tell you the good news about baby genius Ginny Weasley.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week sees Harry attempt to rescue Ginny from her fate in the Chamber. There, he encounters the memory ghost of Tom Riddle, who has been controlling Ginny and forcing her to open the Chamber this whole time. Harry must fight the Basilisk and escape with his friends (plus Professor Lockhart).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.16 The Chamber of Secrets</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/216/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 07:30:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/216/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/216TheChamberOfSecrets.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s Monday and the universe&amp;rsquo;s favorite chapter by chapter Harry Potter podcast, Podtrificus Totalus, is talking giant snakes!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s chapter, things get bad at Hogwarts. Harry and Ron can&amp;rsquo;t find an opportunity to sneak into Moaning Myrtle&amp;rsquo;s bathroom and uncover the Chamber of Secrets. They discover that the monster that has been petrifying their classmates is a basilisk and that Ginny, Ron&amp;rsquo;s younger sister, has been taken to the Chamber. With the threat of Hogwarts closing for good and a reluctant Lockhart dragged along with them, they take the plunge into the Chamber, hoping they can rescue Ginny before it&amp;rsquo;s too late.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.15 Aragog</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/215/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 07:30:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/215/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/215Aragog.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s Monday and Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, is back to talk about some current events and some giant spiders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s chapter, Harry and Ron follow Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s advice to follow the spiders. This brings them into the Forbidden Forest, where they encounter an old friend and a new threat, uncovering some information about when the Chamber was opened last.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.14 Cornelius Fudge</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/214/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 07:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/214/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/214CorneliusFudge.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday and Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, is remaining true to their word to release episodes regularly! What a dream! What a treat for you!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s chapter sees the trio falling complacent, reluctant to ask Hagrid any questions about his expulsion. But when Harry&amp;rsquo;s room is ransacked, Tom Riddle&amp;rsquo;s diary stolen, and Hermione is petrified, Harry and Ron set out to find answers but are interrupted by the appearance of Cornelius Fudge and Lucius Malfoy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.13 The Very Secret Diary</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/213/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 07:30:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/213/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/213TheVerySecretDiary.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday and that means a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, the universe&amp;rsquo;s favorite Harry Potter podcast!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s chapter, Harry finds a mystery diary that belonged to a T.M. Riddle fifty years ago &amp;ndash; the same amount of time that has passed since the Chamber of Secrets was last opened. A Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day disaster ends up revealing the diary&amp;rsquo;s secrets, and Harry learns who opened the Chamber last time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.12 The Polyjuice Potion</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/212/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 07:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/212ThePolyjuicePotion.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday! There&amp;rsquo;s a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus! We are a Harry Potter podcast that reads the books chapter by chapter!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter sees Hermione finally finish brewing the Polyjuice Potion, with relatively positive results. Harry and Ron, disguised as Goyle and Crabbe, infiltrate the Slytherin Common Room, but Malfoy denies any involvement in the attacks, leaving them back at square one of unraveling the mystery of the Chamber of Secrets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.11 The Dueling Club</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/211/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 07:30:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/211/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/211TheDuelingClub.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday and that means yet another episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book. We continue our coverage of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt; with mounting rumors about Harry&amp;rsquo;s connections to the attacks on students. Snape and Lockheart host a disastrous Dueling Club that does little to improve Harry&amp;rsquo;s reputation or the students&amp;rsquo; preparedness, and two more denizens of Hogwarts are petrified by the end of the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.10 The Rogue Bludger</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 07:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/210TheRogueBludger.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, Cassie and Joe stay on topic for their Shakira podcast by discussing Quidditch, broken arms, and the Wagga Wagga Werewolf.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picking up from the previous chapter, Hermione cons Lockheart into signing a note that allows her to get a book out of the Restricted Section of the library. While the trio makes plans to brew the Polyjuice Potion, Harry is harassed by a bludger in his Quidditch match against Slytherin and lands in the Hospital Wing regrowing bones. There, he has an interesting visitor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.9 The Writing on the Wall</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/209/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 07:30:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/209/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/209TheWritingOnTheWall.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, Cassie and Joe debate whether Squibs should be allowed to attend Hogwarts for chapter nine of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Writing on the Wall.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having just been discovered at the scene of Mrs. Norris&amp;rsquo;s petrification, Harry, Ron, and Hermione are interrogated by their professors about their involvement. They&amp;rsquo;re released, but they have questions about the Chamber of Secrets that need answering&amp;ndash;and a mystery they have to solve before all the Muggle-born students in the school are targeted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.8 The Deathday Party</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/208/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 07:30:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/208/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/208TheDeathdayParty.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s episode of Podtrificus Totalus covers the second Halloween that Harry spends at Hogwarts, and it&amp;rsquo;s even spookier than the last! Nearly Headless Nick asks Harry and his friends to attend his Deathday Party, a celebration of the anniversary of his death. There, the kids get a glimpse into the world of ghosts, but as they leave, Harry once again hears the mysterious voice, and they stumble upon poor petrified Mrs. Norris under a message about the Chamber of Secrets being opened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.7 Mudbloods and Murmurs</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/207/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 07:30:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/207/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/207MudbloodsandMurmurs.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, Cassie and Joe talk about racial allegory and The Voice for chapter seven of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Mudbloods and Murmurs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oliver Wood wakes Harry up early for Quidditch practice, but they find that the Slytherins also have a claim on the Quidditch pitch. The team gets into a scrap that ends with Malfoy calling Hermione a Mudblood and Ron burping up slugs. Later, Harry serves his detention with Gilderoy and hears a mysterious voice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.6 Gilderoy Lockhart</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/206/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 16:21:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/206/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/206GilderoyLockhart.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re coming at you a few hours later than usual with a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In chapter six of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;, Ron gets a Howler from Mrs. Weasley and must deal with his broken wand, Harry unwillingly gets a few lessons in fame from Gilderoy Lockhart, and Hermione cleans up the mess of their incompetent Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.5 The Whomping Willow</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/205/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 07:30:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/205/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/205TheWhompingWillow.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and this week we have a super exciting new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book. In this episode, we are joined by our first guest: Zoë from the Tea &amp;amp; Strumpets podcast. We had an amazing chat with Zoë about her history with the Harry Potter series, but if you want to jump straight to the chapter discussion, fast forward in your podcast app to the 24 minute mark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.4 At Flourish and Blotts</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/204/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 07:30:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/204/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/204AtFlourishandBlotts.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, which always brings a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book, by two people who know a medium amount about Harry Potter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, Harry makes an unintended detour on his way to Diagon Alley, and he spots Draco and Lucius Malfoy visiting some unsavory shops to unload some unsavory goods. Harry is rescued by Hagrid, who reunites him with the Weasleys. All visit Flourish and Blotts and meet the new Defense Against the Dark Arts professor, Gilderoy Lockhart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.3 The Burrow</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/203/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 07:30:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/203/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/202DobbysWarning.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and that means a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve finally reached the big one: with the help of Ron and his brothers, Harry visits the Burrow for the first time and spends time with (objectively) the best character in the Harry Potter universe, Molly Weasley. There are also gnomes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.2 Dobby&#39;s Warning</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/202/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 01:19:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/202/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/202DobbysWarning.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and that means a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This episode continues our coverage of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt;. In the second chapter, we meet Dobby the House Elf, who reveals a dangerous plot at Hogwarts that he&amp;rsquo;ll do anything to keep Harry away from &amp;ndash; including spelling out trouble with the Dursleys.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.1 The Worst Birthday</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/201/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 06:30:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/chamber/201TheWorstBirthday.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to begin &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/em&gt; this week on Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On this episode, we cover the rather sparse first chapter of the second book in the series, in which Harry spends his birthday scrubbing floors and tending to gardens in preparation for the Dursley&amp;rsquo;s dinner party.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
