<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prisoner of Azkaban on Podtrificus Totalus</title>
    <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/tags/prisoner-of-azkaban/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prisoner of Azkaban on Podtrificus Totalus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 06:00:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://podtrificustotalus.com/tags/prisoner-of-azkaban/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3.15 The Quidditch Final</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/315/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 06:00:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/315/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/315TheQuidditchFinal.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday and I hate this chapter because it&amp;rsquo;s about Quidditch! Other things happen too, which you can hear about on this week&amp;rsquo;s episode of Podtrificus Totalus, the universe&amp;rsquo;s favorite Harry Potter podcast done book by book, chapter by chapter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bridget Jones&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/em&gt; (2001)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avatar: The Last Airbender&lt;/em&gt; S01E14 &lt;a href=&#34;https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/The_Fortuneteller&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fortuneteller&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; series&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.14 Snape&#39;s Grudge</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/314/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 06:00:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/314/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/314SnapesGrudge.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and Podtrificus Totalus is hitting you with yet another episode of the Wizarding World&amp;rsquo;s favorite Harry Potter podcast!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter sees Harry and Ron continue their grudge match with Hermione despite Hagrid&amp;rsquo;s urgings to make up. Harry chooses to go to Hogsmeade yet again, but when the Invisibility Cloak slips off, Malfoy spots him and runs off to tell Professor Snape. Once apprehended by the Potions master, Harry learns more about his father&amp;rsquo;s history with Snape and why Professor Snape dislikes him so&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.13 Gryffindor versus Ravenclaw</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/313/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 06:00:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/313/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/313GryffindorversusRavenclaw.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and that means it&amp;rsquo;s time to talk about yet another instance of J.K. Rowling doing the worst job she possibly can at representing diverse peoples!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter of &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt;, Gryffindor plays Ravenclaw in Quidditch, and Harry finally gets to put the Firebolt to work. Harry and Ron consider forgiving Hermione, but a bloody mess on Ron&amp;rsquo;s sheets only serves to distance them further. Harry manages to conjure a Patronus successfully, and Ron faces yet another threat while within the common room&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.12 The Patronus</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/312/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 06:00:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/312/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;link&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and we&amp;rsquo;re back after a week off with an extra-long episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done book by book, chapter by chapter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On this week&amp;rsquo;s episode, we cover chapter twelve of Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, &amp;ldquo;The Patronus!&amp;rdquo; In this chapter, Harry begins his anti-Dementor lessons with Professor Lupin, but he hesitates when he realizes that blocking out the Dementors might block him out from ever hearing his parents&amp;rsquo; voices again. Harry and Ron&amp;rsquo;s feud with Hermione over the Firebolt continues, and just when they&amp;rsquo;re about to make up, Ron finds a crime scene in his bedsheets with no sign of Scabbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.11 Firebolt</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/311/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 06:00:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/311/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/311TheFirebolt.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and we&amp;rsquo;re flying in on a speedy (but possibly jinxed?) broomstick with the latest episode of Podtrificus Totalus, the international standard in Harry Potter podcasts done chapter by chapter, book by book!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Harry, upset and enraged by the news of Sirius Black&amp;rsquo;s betrayal, is determined to seek revenge for his parents&amp;rsquo; deaths and take the adults in his life to task for withholding the truth from him. Despite Ron and Hermione&amp;rsquo;s attempts to talk him down, Harry continues to seethe until he is distracted by Buckbeak&amp;rsquo;s impending doom. On Christmas day, Harry receives a mysterious and expensive gift with no note or card, prompting a disagreement with Hermione.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.10 The Marauder&#39;s Map</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 06:00:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/310TheMaraudersMap.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday and it&amp;rsquo;s time to relive childhood trauma with Podtrificus Totalus, the only Harry Potter read along podcast that spends several minutes talking about Pooh Bear hats!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; is one big exposition dump! Harry chats with Lupin about the effect the Dementors have on him, and Lupin agrees to teach Harry how to defend himself against them. Fred and George gift Harry the Marauder&amp;rsquo;s Map which (among other things) shows him the secret passages between Hogwarts and Hogsmeade. Finally, Harry overhears a conversation in the Three Broomsticks which finally reveals the connection between him and Sirius Black.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.9 Grim Defeat</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/309/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 06:00:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/309/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/309GrimDefeat.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, which means a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, Cedric Diggory&amp;rsquo;s favorite Harry Potter re-read podcast!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picking up after Sirius Black attempted to break into the Gryffindor common room, the students are moved into the Great Hall for the night, where Harry overhears an interesting conversation. The next day, Lupin is out sick and Snape subs in for him, abusing students along the way. Gryffindor and Hufflepuff face off in a Quidditch match with disastrous results, and a beloved companion leaves us forever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.8 Flight of the Fat Lady</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/308/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 06:00:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/308/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/308FlightoftheFatLady.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday and we&amp;rsquo;re back at it again at Podtrificus Totalus, the only Harry Potter podcast that spends roughly half the runtime debating the pedagogical methods at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter takes &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt; into Hogwarts and keeps Harry out of the Halloween trip to Hogsmeade. As he mopes about the castle, he ends up in Professor Lupin&amp;rsquo;s office for tea and a conversation about fear. While Lupin believes Harry wise for fearing the Dementors most of all, the end of the chapter should perhaps heighten Harry&amp;rsquo;s fear about Sirius Black, who attacks the portrait of the Fat Lady that guards Gryffindor Common Room&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.7 The Boggart in the Wardrobe</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/307/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 06:30:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/307/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/307TheBoggartintheWardrobe.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another Monday, another episode of Podtrificus Totalus, the best Harry Potter podcast in the known galaxy!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week, we cover chapter seven of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt;, which puzzles us with Shrinking Solutions and Boggarts. We face each of our worst fears to give you plenty of background knowledge, analysis, and discussion of the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.6 Talons and Tea Leaves</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/306/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:30:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/306/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/306TalonsandTeaLeaves.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;of Azkaban, &amp;ldquo;Talons and Tea Leaves,&amp;rdquo; in which Harry, Ron, and Hermione start their third year at Hogwarts. They begin new courses (some more than others), and Hermione must decide where she draws the line between magic and card tricks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hp-lexicon.org/character/parkinson-family/pansy-parkinson/&#34;&gt;Pansy Parkinson&lt;/a&gt; on the Harry Potter Lexicon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archiveofourown.org/works/2330390&#34;&gt;ugly: in defense of pansy parkinson&lt;/a&gt; by dirgewithoutmusic on AO3&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.5 The Dementor</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/305/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 05:00:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/305/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/305TheDementor.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday &amp;ndash; you know us, you love us, it&amp;rsquo;s time for Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done book by book, chapter by chapter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week we cover chapter five of &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt;, in which Harry encounters a clumsy metaphor for depression &amp;ndash; I mean, a new and foreboding creature in the magical world! &amp;ndash; meets his new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher, and eats some chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.4 The Leaky Cauldron</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/304/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 05:00:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/304/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/304TheLeakyCauldron.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and that&amp;rsquo;s the day that the Wizarding World&amp;rsquo;s favorite Harry Potter podcast releases. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a brand new episode of Podtrificus Totalus!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week, we cover the fourth chapter in &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Leaky Cauldron!&amp;rdquo; This finds Harry with new freedoms as he temporarily lives in and explores Diagon Alley. He eventually meets up with the Weasleys and Hermione, andhe learns a dark secret about Sirius Black&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.3 The Knight Bus</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/303/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 06:00:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/303/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;link&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and you know what that means&amp;hellip; a new episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast made for your listening pleasure!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s episode covers chapter three of &lt;em&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;The Knight Bus,&amp;rdquo; which finds Harry on the run after blowing up his Aunt Marge. Harry prepares to live his life as an outlaw as he rides the Knight Bus to London, where he encounters an unexpected face&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.2 Aunt Marge&#39;s Big Mistake</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/302/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 06:00:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/302/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/302AuntMargesBigMistake.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and that means it&amp;rsquo;s time for another episode of Podtrificus Totalus, a Harry Potter podcast done chapter by chapter, book by book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, Harry continues to spend a painful summer with the Dursleys, with the notable inclusion of Vernon&amp;rsquo;s sister Marge. Harry struggles to maintain his cool as Marge berates him, with explosive results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.1 Owl Post</title>
      <link>https://podtrificustotalus.com/301/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 06:00:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://podtrificustotalus.com/301/</guid>
      <description>&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://cdn.podtrificustotalus.com/prisoner/301OwlPost.mp3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, and Podtrificus Totalus is back! This chapter begins our coverage of Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, the third book in the series. We begin by covering the release of Prisoner of Azkaban and the writing process behind it, then launch into the full chapter discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make a number of references to outside sources and popular culture, which are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20131209001627/http://theremembrall.org/books/azkaban/&#34;&gt;Prisoner of Azkaban was delayed&lt;/a&gt; from The Remembrall, archived by the Wayback Machine&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
